Now, this video might get me banned or
in trouble, and I think you're going to
question everything that you thought you
knew about modern medicine. I'm going to
share just the highlights from this book
right here, which I'll put a link down
below. There's a lot more details on
this topic, but I'm going to cover the
highlights. Typically, the RDAs for
vitamin D are about 600 IUs. They stand
for international units. It's an
arbitrary number which basically a group
of people in a committee voted on it.
And I really believe it was originally
designed to scare people from taking too
much of certain things. But at the end
of this video, I'm going to share with
you who really started this whole thing
and it will all make sense. And if we
just take a look at 600 IUs,
international units, how many milligrams
is that? That's just a little bit more
than onetenth of one milligram. That's a
very small amount. For the last hundred
years, vitamin D has been a very
controversial topic because
I believe it helps so many people in so
many ways. We use sunbathing called
heliootherapy back in the early 1900s.
This was before vaccines and this was
before antibiotics. And they would heal
up their TB and their asthma,
osteoporosis,
tooth decay, psoriasis, mood issues,
diabetes, heart disease, and even
cancer. And then what happened? We're
told to stay out of the sun. Here, take
your sunblock. Vitamin D could be toxic.
What you need to know is 600 IUs is
basically standing out in the sun in the
summer 1.8 8 minutes, less than 2
minutes. 10,000 IUs is standing out in
the summer sun for about 30 minutes. But
in the last 100 years, this number 600
IUs has been pushed on people. That's
what you need. And because of some
vitamin D toxicity issues, the
government commissioned the University
of Illinois Chicago to do a study on the
toxicity of vitamin D. The previous
reports of vitamin D toxicity was
related to improper production
techniques. So it really wasn't about
the vitamin D itself. It was in the
manufacturing of vitamin D. Now this
study that they did went on for 9 years.
It involved hundreds of doctors,
773 patients, 63 dogs. Take a wild guess
what type of dosage they use for vitamin
D. 200,000
to 1 million IUs. Well, guess what? They
did not find any toxicity. Now, what you
have to realize is that vitamin D3 is
very special in that it's an immune
modulator. The Institute of Health is
kind of a governing body and they're the
ones who recommend 600 IUs of vitamin
D3. Here's the problem with those
numbers and their evaluation. There was
two other organizations who re-evaluated
their data and found that they made some
mistakes. Well, was 600 IUs should have
been 8,895
IUs. Let's take a look at one of the
major vitamin D researchers.
>> And he invited me to talk. I got up and
presented this data to, you know, these
were the top vitamin D researchers in
the world all assembled there. It was
vicious. The attacks of how vitamin D
doesn't do this. How could you say this?
I said, I'm just presenting the data
that we have assembled. You're walking
on guys careers that have spent their
whole career doing this stuff. They
never conceived that this could be true.
You know, you don't know what you're
doing. Well, the government wasted a
whole lot of money here for you to
conduct these worthless studies. The
same type of thing happened to uh the
professor who discovered folates was
chastised and not believed for for
decades that how could a nutrient have
this kind of an effect. Of course, he
turned out to be true, but it was the
same sort of attacks. Take a look at
these interesting graphs. Zero is is
right in the center of these graphs uh
by the equator where you have the most
sun and the most vitamin D. So MS,
breast cancer, colorctyl cancer and
diabetes lowest risk at the equator. So
this just gives an interesting
correlation between latitude and certain
diseases. Now I want to share some
additional things. In 1900 to 1910
a lot of people got ricketetts. It was
common back then. 1918 to 1920 they use
sun therapy in cod liver oil for
ricketetts. 1922 they discovered vitamin
D. 1946 the number 400 IUs was
recommended to prevent ricketetts. 1950
to 1970, despite the increased awareness
that vitamin D goes beyond just bone
health, they kept the numbers for
vitamin D at 400 IUs. 1980, there were
more benefits for vitamin D for your
immune system, for other chronic
diseases, but they kept the same 400 IUs
for vitamin D3. Then in 1997, the
Institute of Medicine updated the RDAs.
They wanted to introduce something new
called the adequate intake because they
said the RDAs weren't very scientific.
So, take a wild guess what they
recommended at this point. 200 IUs for
adults, 400 IUs if you're 51 to 70, and
600 IUs for over 70. Finally, in 2010,
they went uh up to 600 IUs for adults
under 70 and 800 if you're over 70. Now,
this whole time they're recommending 400
IUs. There are three medications
that were used on a regular basis and
take a wild guess what they were.
Vitamin D at 50,000 IUs. So you can take
it if it's prescribed through
medication, but everyone else, you know,
takes 400 because of the toxicity of
anything more. I mean, think about in
the 80s this huge campaign to stay out
of the sun, take sunblock. The sun will
kill you. You're going to get skin
cancer. Melanoma, which is the number
one skin cancer. It develops in areas
where you're not exposed to sun.
Personally, my viewpoint on melanomas,
it's really a vitamin D deficiency.
Vitamin D is needed in 2700
different genes. There are so many
barriers for absorbing vitamin D3. You
have the difficulty getting vitamin D in
food. You have this thing called vitamin
D resistance, which a lot of people have
genetically where the vitamin D receptor
won't receive the vitamin D. The darker
the skin, the less absorption of vitamin
D you get. The older the skin, the less
vitamin D you create. The more you
weigh, the less vitamin D you're going
to absorb because vitamin D gets diluted
into the fat cells. But it's very
obvious to me that big pharma, modern
medicine want you to take extremely low
doses of vitamin D, if any vitamin D at
all. So, this is just scratching the
surface. If you want the complete data
on this history, check out this book
right here. I'll put a link down below
in the description.
Hey, before you leave, I just wanted to
give you a little quick history on some
of the books that I wrote. This was one
of the first books. It's called Dr.
Burke Body Shapes. It was my attempt at
um writing about body types. Uh what was
very interesting about this book is I
actually did all the images myself. Uh
don't ask me why. Um they look actually
not quite as professional as some of the
uh images that I have in the new book.
But anyway, this is my first attempt
right here called Dr. Burke's Body Shape
Diets. Uh, and then I wrote a book um,
more extensive called The Seven
Principles of Fat Burning. I don't even
have a copy anymore actually um because
it's outdated. Uh, the next book uh, I
put about a thousand hours into this one
right here called The New Body Type
Guide. Major updates on the body types.
Uh, I put a lot of energy into this. Uh,
it has professional images, graphics,
all sorts of things. Now, the problem
with this book is it doesn't really
describe what this is really about. Body
types are only a small portion of what's
in this book. And that's why I changed
the name to the healthy keto plan. Okay?
If you happen to have this book, you
don't really need this book because
there's some only very, very minor
updates. But if you don't have this, you
need to get this one right here. Um,
this book goes into every single detail
that you would ever want to know about.
It goes into the seven principles of fat
burning. Goes into hormones, uh, the
body types, the basic keto plan. It goes
into intermittent fasting. I talk about
the 10 fat burning triggers and blockers
and fat burning strategies with a lot of
details in every single chapter. I go
into body issues that interfere with
losing weight. Um, there's very few
people that just have a weight problem.
They have a lot of body issues, whether
it's sleeping problems, uh, stress
problems, inflammation,
menopause. I cover that extensively in
this book. Then I talk about how to get
rid of stress and I show you a
technique. Uh, then I get into
exercising, and then I have a lot of
really good recipes in this book as
well. So, uh, this is a good reference
guide. Um, on my website, if you get
this book, you get this one free. It's
called Healthy Keto Intermittent
Fasting. This is the shortcut uh quick
guide to this book. And uh the reason I
created this book is to have you within
45 minutes learn how to do keto, okay,
in intermittent fasting, exactly what
you need to do. Then you can fill in the
blanks with this book right here. So,
right now I'm doing a special. If you
get this book, you get this one totally
free. Or you can go to Amazon and get
these individually. So, I just want to
clarify the difference between this book
and this updated one right here. If you
don't have this, you need to get this
right here. That way, you can get the
exact correct information to do it
healthfully.